Dr Jon G. C. Kragskow MRSC

Department of Chemistry, University of Bath, UK

www.kragskow.dev jgck20@bath.ac.uk

A fast and enthusiastic learner with a strong background in computational and theoretical chemistry, particularly as applied to magnetic and spectroscopic properties of transition metal and lanthanide systems. Passionate about building well-documented and open-source tools which make research easier, clearer, and more approachable. Committed to education, particularly through the creation of modern and interactive digital resources.

EMPLOYMENT

UNIVERSITY OF BATH
Bath, UK

Lecturer in Computational Chemistry

September 2024-

Teaching and Research Lectureship

UNIVERSITY OF BATH (Dr Elizaveta Suturina)

Bath, UK

Post-Doctoral Research Associate (EPSRC)

January 2023-Sept. 2024

- Implemented new computational tools for routine simulation and analysis of paramagnetic NMR spectra in both biological and chemical systems.
- Calculated and simulated of magnetic properties of exchange-coupled transition metal complexes using *ab initio* methods and spin-Hamiltonian modelling.
- Participation in academic exchange visits to Florence, Italy (protein NMR experiments) and Bordeaux, France (proton NMR and magnetochemistry experiments).
- Tutor in first year physical chemistry, and demonstrator/contributor for second year computational chemistry lab experiments.

THE UNIVERSITY OF MANCHESTER (Prof. Nicholas Chilton)

Manchester, UK

Post-Doctoral Research Associate (ERC)

April 2022-October 2022

- Modelled magnetic behaviour of molecular nanomagnets using *ab initio* quantum chemistry, particularly in the solid-state.
- Led development of magnetochemistry software such as ccfit2, a python package for fitting experimental magnetic data
- Trained of group members in python and Fortran software development and best practices for code deployment and version control through code-review sessions, documentation, and workshops.
- Maintained and architected group subversion and git code repositories and created automated pipelines for code documentation and release.

EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY OF MANCHESTER (Prof. Nicholas Chilton)

Manchester, UK

PhD in Chemistry - "Chemical Control of Spin-Phonon Coupling" (EPSRC/Doctoral Scholarship)

September 2018-April 2022

- Calculated spin-phonon coupling (SPC) in lanthanide coordination complexes using *ab initio* quantum chemistry and spin-Hamiltonian approaches, developed methodologies and software for the simulation of SPC-derived properties such as magnetic relaxation rates and magnetic field dependent infrared spectroscopy data.
- Collaborated with experimental groups in Xi'an Jiaotong University (China), the National High Magnetic Field lab (Florida, United States), and University of Copenhagen (Denmark).
- Demonstrated in 2nd year undergraduate lab (MATLAB programming; marking, viva voce). Overhauled course for distance learning.

THE UNIVERSITY OF MANCHESTER

Manchester, UK

MChem in Chemistry

September 2014-June 2018

- Degree Classification: First Class.
- Outstanding Academic Achievement Award (top 0.5% of graduating students in Faculty)

Programming Languages

Beginner JavaScript, Docker, flask, Apache, C++

Intermediate HTML, CSS, Qt, Bash

Experienced Python, Fortran90, Git, Subversion, make, MATLAB, GitLab CI/CD

Open-Source Software Development

ccfit2 A python package for working with experimental magnetometry data. Users can input a magnetometer

output file and obtain a fitted plot of their data using a single command and an interactive interface. Thanks to its modular design and rich documentation, ccfit2 can be included in users own python code with ease.

Waveplot An online wavefunction viewer which demonstrates simple concepts in quantum chemistry. Waveplot is built

with students in mind and features the model quantum systems they encounter in introductory quantum chemistry. Students can manipulate input variables, plots, and download raw data to use in their own work.

AtomAccess A python package which quantifies steric hindrance at chemical centres using raytracing. I wrote

AtomAccess to be fast and user-friendly through either its simple web-interface, or through command-line

and scripting.

Tau A C++/Fortan90 program for the simulation of magnetic relaxation rates. Tau uses *ab initio* spin-phonon

coupling data to accurately simulate magnetic relaxation under a range of conditions using a semi-classical

master equation.

FIRMS_SIM A Fortran90 program for the simulation of magnetic field dependent infrared spectroscopy. FIRMS_SIM uses

ab initio spin-phonon coupling data to simulate the electronic and vibrational signals observed in the

infrared spectra of molecules under applied magnetic fields.

Technical

Quantum Chemistry High-level knowledge of computational and quantum chemistry methods (HF, DFT, MCSCF), and experience

in using established programs (Gaussian, OpenMOLCAS, ORCA).

Magnetism Experienced in analysis and workup of experimental magnetometry data (AC susceptibility, DC decay,

magnetisation and susceptibility). Expert knowledge of phenomenological and spin-Hamiltonian modelling

techniques.

HPC Proficient HPC user, familiar with a variety of schedulers and systems of differing scale (AWS, Azure, local

clusters, Tier-2 HPC). Experience in creating and maintaining group-level clusters/systems.

FUNDING SECURED

2022 Royal Society of Chemistry - Researcher Mobility Grant (£500)

2019 European Cost Action Group on Molecular Spintronics (MOLSPIN) – Travel Support (£500)

2017 Royal Society of Chemistry - Undergraduate Summer Research Bursary (£1.5k)

2016 The University of Manchester - Undergraduate Departmental Research Bursary (£1k)

AWARDS_

The University of Manchester – Outstanding Postgraduate Acad	emic Achievement Award
---	------------------------

The University of Manchester – President's Doctoral Scholarship

2018 The University of Manchester – Outstanding Undergraduate Academic Achievement Award

PUBLICATIONS

- 13. G. K. Gransbury, S. C. Corner, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, P. Evans, H. Yeung, W. J. A. Blackmore, G. F. S. Whitehead, I. J. Vitorica-Yrezabal, M. S. Oakley, N. F. Chilton and D. P. Mills, *J. Am. Chem. Soc.*, 2023, **145**, 41, 22814–22825
- 12. R. Nabi, J. K. Staab, A. Mattioni, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, D. Reta, J. M. Skelton and N. F. Chilton, *J. Am. Chem. Soc.*, 2023, **145**, 45, 24558–24567
- 11. B. Alnami, J. G. C. Kragskow, J. K. Staab, J. M. Skelton and N. F. Chilton, J. Am. Chem. Soc., 2023, 145, 25, 13632-13639
- 10. J. G. C. Kragskow, A. Mattioni, J. K. Staab, D. Reta, J. M. Skelton and N. F. Chilton, Chem. Soc. Rev., 2023, 52, 4567
- 9. W J. A. Blackmore, G. K. Gransbury, P. Evans, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, D. P. Mills, N. F. Chilton, *Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.*, 2023, **25**, 16735-16744
- 8. K. R. McClain, H. Kwon, K. Chakarawet, R. Nabi, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, N. F. Chilton, R. D. Britt, J. R. Long and B. G. Harvey, *J. Am. Chem. Soc.*, 2023, **145**, 8996–9002
- 7. **J. G. C. Kragskow**, J. Marbey, C. D. Buch, J. Nehrkorn, M. Ozerov, S. Piligkos, S. Hill and N. F. Chilton, *Nat. Commun.*, 2022, **13**, 825
- 6. C. A. Gould, K. R. McClain, D. Reta, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, D. A. Marchiori, E. Lachman, E.-S. Choi, J. G. Analytis, R. D. Britt, N. F. Chilton, B. G. Harvey and J. R. Long, *Science*, 2022, **375**, 198-202
- 5. D. Reta, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, N. F. Chilton, J. Am. Chem. Soc., 2021, **143**, 5943–5950
- 4. K.-X. Yu, J. G. C. Kragskow, Y.-S. Ding, Y.-Q. Zhai, D. Reta, N. F. Chilton, Y.-Z. Zheng, *Chem*, 2020, 6, 1–17
- 3. C. A. P. Goodwin, B. L. L. Réant, G. F. Vettese, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, M. J. Giansiracusa, I. M. Dimucci, K. M. Lancaster, D. P. Mills, S. Sproules, *Inorg. Chem.*, 2020, **59**, 7571–7583
- 2. H. M. Nicholas, C. A. P. Goodwin, J. G. C. Kragskow, S. J. Lockyer, D. P. Mills, *Molecules*, 2018, 23, 1138
- 1. C. A. P. Goodwin, B. L. L. Réant, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, I. M. DiMucci, K. M. Lancaster, D. P. Mills and S. Sproules, *Dalton Trans.*, 2018, 47, 10613–1062

PRESENTATIONS_

Invited Talks

2024 Magnetic Molecules: Structure, Spectroscopy, and Dynamics

Donostia International Physics Centre, Donostia, Spain

Contributed Talks

2022 Ultrahard magnetism from mixed-valence dilanthanide complexes with metal-metal bonding

7th European Conference on Molecular Magnetism, Rennes

Vibronic coupling in a 4f qubit

American Physical Society March Meeting, Chicago

2021 Ab initio relaxation dynamics in Lanthanide Single Molecule Magnets

Department of Chemistry Postgraduate Symposium, The University of Manchester

Vibronic coupling in a 4f qubit

 $17^{th}\ International\ Conference\ on\ Molecule\ Based\ Magnets\ Rising\ Star\ Symposium,\ The\ University\ of\ Manchester$

2021 Enhancing Magnetic Hysteresis in Single-Molecule Magnets by Ligand Functionalization

Department of Chemistry Staff Symposium, The University of Manchester

2018 Understanding the Crystal Field of Metal Complexes

Midlands Computational Chemistry Conference, Nottingham Trent University

Posters

- 2024 Understanding the Electronic Structures of Transition Metal Complexes using Paramagnetic NMR Spectroscopy BOOK-D 2024, CRPP, Bordeaux
- 2024 Understanding the Electronic Structures of Transition Metal Complexes using Paramagnetic NMR Spectroscopy
 Spin Meeting 2024, The University of Manchester
- 2023 Understanding the Electronic Structures of Transition Metal Complexes using Paramagnetic NMR Spectroscopy
 19th European Magnetic Resonance Congress, Glasgow
- Ab initio Relaxation Dynamics of Dysprosium(III) Single Molecule Magnets

7th European Conference on Molecular Magnetism, University of Florence